《顿悟》  今晚9点开场
各就各位
Places, everyone.
The Beatles - "Golden Slumbers"
♪Once there was a way♪
♪To get back homeward♪
♪To get back home♪
♪Sleep pretty darling do not cry♪
♪And I will sing a lullabye♪
就是这一刻
This was it.
一切开始的地方
The moment it all began.
一个普通的小家伙
The moment an ordinary little guy
爱上了剧院
fell in love with the theater.
爱上了这里的一切
Everything about it.
灯光闪烁  场景变换
The lights, the way the scenery moved,
甚至气息
even the smell.
他只有六岁
He was only six years old,
可是他成为第一只太空考拉的梦想
but his plans to become the first koala bear
突然间消散了
in space were suddenly toast.
有些人可能会说
Some folks may have said
他成了这座城市最了不起的剧院经理
he grew up to be the greatest showman the city has ever seen.
有些人称他为梦想家  先行者
Some called him a visionary, a Maverick.
当然了  也有人说他又固执又疯狂
sure, some folks said he was as crazy as he was stubborn,
但要我说  美妙的奇观可不是凭空变来的
but I say wonder and magic don't come easy, pal.
而且绝不会有人怀疑
And, oh, there would never be any doubt,
巴斯特·穆恩的大名必将登上
the name Buster Moon would go down
娱乐界史册
in entertainment history.
我最清楚了
And I should know,
-因为我就是巴斯特...  -穆恩
- because I am Buster... - Moon!
开门啊
Open this door!
早上好  穆恩先生
Good morning, Mr. Moon.
克劳利夫人  外边什么情况
Miss Crawly. What, uh... What's going on?
有许多动物想要见您  穆恩先生
You got a lot of animals waiting to see you, Mr. Moon.
是吗
I do?
天哪  还真是
Holy moly, I really do.
是  都是上一场演出的工作人员
Yeah, it's the stage crew from your last show.
他们说您给的支票被退回了
They say their paychecks bounced.
告诉他们我会给银行打电话
Tell 'em I'll call up the bank and make sure
立刻付清他们的全部薪水
they're paid tout de suite.
我把银行的朱迪斯的来电
I got Judith from the bank
帮您转到二号线了  先生
holding on line two right now, sir.
我得过会儿给她打回去了
Actually, I'm gonna have to call her back.
这次我怎么跟她说
What should I tell her this time?
告诉她巴斯特·穆恩出去吃饭了
Tell her Buster Moon is out to lunch.
穆恩  把门打开
Moon! Open this door!
赶紧的  穆恩
Come on, Moon!
我知道你在里面
I know you're in there!
穆恩  把门打开
Moon! Open this door!
The Spencer Davis Group - "Gimme Some Lovin'"
♪Well my temperature's rising and my feet on the floor♪
《欢乐好声音》
♪Twenty people rockin' and there wanna go more♪
♪Let me in baby I don't know what you've got♪
♪But you'd better take it easy this place is hot♪
♪Then I so glad we made it♪
♪So glad we made it♪
♪You gotta♪
♪Gimme some lovin'♪
♪Everyday♪
The Zombies - "The Way I Feel Inside"
♪In your mind could you ever be♪
♪Really close to me♪
♪I can tell the way you smile♪
♪If I feel that I♪
♪Could be certain then♪
♪I would say the things♪
♪I want to say to...♪
我怎么听着有人在唱歌
thought I heard someone singing there.
管他呢
Ah, whatever.
伙计们  听着  别动
Guys, listen. Stay where you are.
有警察
The cops are here in...
你们干什...
What are you...?
-不许动  -我来抓他
- Hold it right there! - Yeah, I'll get him!
快走  快走  快走
Go, go, go!
乔尼  我们不是让你望风吗
Johnny, you were supposed to be keeping a lookout!
对不起  爸
Sorry, dad.
你的面具呢
And where's your mask?
♪Do you ever feel♪
Katy Perry - "Firework"
♪Like a plastic bag♪
♪Drifting through the wind♪
♪Wanting to start again♪
♪Do you ever feel♪
♪Feel so paper thin♪
快看  我是妈妈
Look at me. I'm mommy!
卡斯帕  从桌子上下来
Caspar, get off the table.
萝丝塔  你看到我的车钥匙了吗
Rosita, have you seen my car keys?
诺曼  你告诉他们
Norman, would you please tell them
我歌唱得好不好
what a good singer I am?
没错  你唱得真好  亲爱的
Oh, yeah, you were great, honey.
对了  卫生间的水池又堵了
By the way, the bathroom sink is blocked again.
再见  亲爱的
Bye, honey!
Garth Jennings & David Bassett - "I Don't Wanna"
♪One, two, one, two, three, four♪
♪I don't wanna talk to you♪
♪Nothing to say♪
♪I don't wana walk with you♪
♪Outta my way♪
♪I'm not gonna fight with ya♪
♪I don't wanna play♪
♪I don't need anyone else♪
♪I live my life by myself♪
♪I can't stand a thing that you say♪
♪I'm not listening any...♪
我了个天哪
Oh, my gosh.
你们还好意思自称是音乐家
I thought you guys said you were musicians.
艾什  亲爱的
Ash, babe,
我是主唱  好吗
I'm the lead singer, okay?
你唱好合声就好了
Just stick to the backing vocals.
对不起  我唱得太投入了
Sorry, I... I get carried away.
我知道了  好吧
Yeah, I know, right?
你有点把我的歌毁了  你知道吗
It just kind of ruins my song, you know?
-祝我生日快乐  -祝你生日快乐
- Happy birthday to me. - Happy birthday to you.
祝外公生日快乐
Happy birthday to grandpa
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
怎么了
What?
来  许个愿望吧
Come on, make your wish.
我的愿望是你去参加合唱团
I wish you'd join a choir.
或是本地乐队什么的
A local band or something.
-我试过了  -得了吧
- I tried. - Bah.
爸爸  我们已经谈过这个问题了
Hey, hey, dad, we've been over this.
她有点害羞又怎样
So she's a little shy. So what?
如果我有米娜的好嗓子  我早就是大明星了
If I had a voice like Meena's, I'd be a superstar by now!
唱就好了嘛
Just sing it.
肯定好听  外公
So you would, grandpa.
现在吹蜡烛吧
Now blow out your candles.
一毛钱
A penny?
你好大的胆子
How dare you!
我好歹是林肯音乐学院科班出身
I happen to have studied at the Lincoln school of music.
对不起  我现在只有这么多
Sorry, it's-it's all I got right now.
是这样吗
Oh, is that so?
-好啊  证明一下  伙计  -什么
- All right, prove it, pal. - What?
-立即掏空你的口袋  -我找找
- Empty your pockets right now. - Trying to find...
-你这都是堆什么玩意  -我找找
- Wh-what is this you got here? -Just trying to find...
你用这个吸什么
What do you smoke out of this?
这是我的吸入器
That's my inhaler.
我就知道
I knew it!
你们都看到了
You all saw it.
大家都看到了
You all saw it right here.
猴子说谎了
The monkey lied.
我不记得我还带钱了
I forgot I had that.
下次别再以大欺小了
And next time, pick on someone your own size!
恶霸
Bully!
花枝居
好好照顾她  好吗
Take care of her, will you?
她是有点破旧生锈  但可是经典款
She may look old and rusty, but she is a classic.
维瓦尔第 - 《四季-春》
好了  听着
Okay, listen.
我们都知道  我的剧院最近
We both know that my theater has been going through
经营有些困难  可是老话唱得好
some pretty rough times lately, but as the saying goes,
"阳光总在风雨后"
"For every cloud, a silver lining."
-我们有...  -等一下  巴斯特
- We've got... - Hold on right there, Buster.
我爸爸  他一听说我今天要来见你
My dad, he heard I was gonna see you today,
就跟我说  "艾迪  你告诉那考拉
and he was all like, "Eddie, you tell that koala
我不会再赞助他那些演出了
I'm not funding any more of those shows,
不变了"  这是他的原话
and that's final." Those were his words.
好吧  你爸爸是对的
Well, your dad's right.
问题就出在这些演出上面
Those shows were the problem.
《消耗战》  《萝丝谢幕》
War of attrition. Rosie takes a bow.
如今没人愿意看这种东西了
I mean, nobody wants to see that stuff anymore.
那我该怎么办呢
So, what do I do?
-关门吗  -不
- Quit? - No.
我要办一场人们无法拒绝的演出  那就是
I give 'em a show they cannot resist, which is gonna be...
我们一会儿再点餐
J-just one more minute, s'il vous plait.
谢谢
Merci.
别说法语  这儿的人都讲英语
Don't speak French. They speak English here.
我的下一场演出将会是  鼓点敲起来
Now, my next show is gonna be-- drumroll, please...
歌唱比赛
...a singing competition.
A singing competition?
这年头谁还会来看歌唱比赛
Who wants to see another one of those?
人人都想看  想一想
Everyone! J-j-just think.
你的邻居  那个百货商店的经理
Your neighbor, the-the-the grocery store manager,
还有那边那只鸡
that-that-that chicken-- right there!
这座城市里的每个人都有机会上镜
Everyone in this city gets a shot
成为我的舞台上的主角
at being a star live on my stage.
巴斯特  这主意太糟糕了
Buster, this is a terrible idea.
不  一点儿都不糟
Oh, no, it's not.
高雅艺术来源于真实生活
Real talent from real life.
这才是观众想看的  我就给他们这个机会
That's what audiences want, and I'm gonna give it to 'em!
我们能先离开这儿吗
C-can we please just get out of here?
你不想吃点东西吗
Don't you want to eat?
想是想  可是我们吃不起
Yeah, but we can't afford any of this.
我知道  所以...
Yes, I know, and that's why...
我带了三明治
I brought sandwiches.
这里不许吃外带食品
That's not allowed.
怎么  你不喜欢夹花生酱果冻吗
What, you don't like peanut butter and jelly?
很抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
好吧  我还有奶油芝士和香蕉
Okay, look. I got cream cheese, I got banana...
-你还好吧  -我很好  不能再好了
- You okay? - Yep. Never better.
克劳利夫人
Miss crawly?
你好
Hello?
哪位
who is it?
是我
It's me.
你的老板  穆恩先生
Your boss, Mr. Moon.
-您好  穆恩先生  -听我说
- Oh, hello, Mr. Moon. - There we go.
我需要你在我们的宣传单上
Now, I need you to add the following information
-添加一些信息  -好的  先生
- to our publicity flyers. - Yes, sir.
歌唱比赛的冠军
The winner of the singing contest
将会赢得高达...
will receive a grand prize of...
935块
$935.
有点儿少
Gonna need more than that.
等一下
Just a second.
好了
There.
1000元巨奖
$1,000.
-你记下了吗  -1000块
- You got that? - - Uh, $1,000...
把剩下的纸全都给我印了
Print 'em up on every single sheet of paper we have left
然后立刻把这些传单发出去  好吗
and let's spread the word right away, okay?
好的  先生
Yes, uh, yes, sir.
好了  出来吧
Okay. Come on out of there.
十万大奖
转运的清风
The winds of change.
没错  只要这次演出成功
Yep, when this show's a hit,
我就能把你好好粉刷一遍了
I'm gonna get you a fresh coat of paint.
传单印得怎么样了  克劳利夫人
How are we doing with those flyers, miss crawly?
好的  先生  一切就绪
Oh, yes, sir. We're all good to go here.
克劳利夫人  不要  不要  不要
Miss Crawly, no! No, no, no, no, no, no!
哎呀
Oopsie-Daisy.
这样倒也能把消息传出去
Oh, well, I guess that's one way to spread the word.
兰斯  快看
Hey, Lance, look at this.
艾什  宝贝
Ash, babe, hey!
-你把钱取了  -是的
- You make a withdrawal! - Yeah.
米娜
Meena!
歌唱大赛海选
十万大奖等你拿
你没长眼...
What do you think you...?
是的
Yeah.
歌唱大赛海选
十万大奖等你拿
开始工作吧
Let's go to work.
蜥蜴疯老太登场
And cue the crazy old lizard.
早上好  穆恩先生
Good morning, Mr. Moon.
当然好了  克劳利夫人
Indeed it is, Miss Crawly.
你也早上好
Top of the morning to you.
我给您冲了咖啡
I made you some coffee.
是吗  咖啡在哪儿呢
You did? Where is it?
我爬楼梯的时候有一点口渴
Oh, I got a little thirsty on the way up those stairs.
-我现在可以开门了吗  -开门
- Shall I go open the doors now? - The doors?
有很多动物在门外排着长队
Well, you've got a lot of animals waiting in line
等着海选呢  穆恩先生
to audition, Mr. Moon.
是吗
I do?
天啊  还真是
Holy moly, I really do.
我向你保证  艾迪  我没开玩笑
I swear to you, Eddie, this is no joke.
不信你自己过来看
Look, just get down here and see for yourself.
我要走了
I gotta go.
就是这样  克劳利夫人
This is it, Miss Crawly.
快给我到楼下去  打开大门
Get your scaly tail downstairs and throw those doors open wide.
每次一位  谢谢配合
Okay, uh, one at a time, please.
安静点儿
Calm down.
♪Got me looking so crazy right now, your love's♪
Beyoncé - "Crazy in Love"
♪Got me looking so crazy right now♪
♪Got me looking so crazy right now, your touch♪
Lady Gaga - "Bad Romance"
♪Rah rah ah-ah-ah♪
♪Ro mah ro-mah-mah♪
♪Gaga oh-la-la♪
♪Want your bad romance♪
Alex Van Halen / Edward Van Halen / David Lee Roth - "Jump"
♪Jump, jump, jump♪
♪Might as well jump♪
再见伊吉  再见佩里  再见卡拉
Bye, Iggy. Bye, Perry. Bye, Carla.
再见盖尔  再见罗利  再见米基
Bye, Gail. Bye, Rory. Bye, Mickey.
再见莫伊  再见尼尔森  再见汉娜
Bye, moe. Bye, Nelson. Bye, Hannah.
再见  泰斯  再见  卡斯帕
Bye, Tess. Bye-bye, caspar.
歌唱大赛海选
十万大奖等你拿
Seal - "Kiss From A Rose"
♪Baby♪
♪I compare you to a kiss from a rose on the grey♪
♪L U C K♪
きゃりーぱみゅぱみゅ - "きらきらキラー"
♪I love my shoes♪
Donovan - "I Love My Shirt"
Crazy Town - "Butterfly"
♪Come on lady come come my lady♪
♪You are my butterfly sugar baby♪
本地歌唱大赛海选  众人参与渴望当明星
我们再听听队列中其他选手怎么说
let's hear from a few more of the folks in line.
-您呢  先生  -好吧  鲍勃
- What about you, sir? -Well, Bob,
我是一家顶尖医药公司的实验室技术员
I'm a lab technician for a leading pharmaceutical company,
可是我天赋异禀
but I was born with a gift.
那就是唱歌
And that gift is to sing.
Shooby Taylor - "Stout-Hearted Men"
♪Plav da shree, loh ku pah♪
♪Dav du sah! Soo-da-li dwee-daht♪
♪Soo-da-li doo-ton plah-blah♪
Nicki Minaj - "Anaconda"
♪Oh my gosh♪
♪Look at her butt♪
♪Look at her...♪
♪I live my life by myself♪
Garth Jennings & David Bassett - "I Don't Wanna"
♪Can't stand a thing that you say♪
♪I am not listening anyway♪
♪I am not listening anyway yeah♪
♪Lollipop Lollipop Oh Lolli-Lolli-Lolli♪
The Chordettes - "Lollipop"
爸  我出去一下
Oi, dad. Just going out.
早点回来  我叫了其他人过来
Well, don't be long. I got the gang coming over.
♪Lollipop Lollipop Oh Lolli-Lolli-Lolli♪
车库
是这样  我估计你们肯定
Well, look, I mean, I'm sure you're gonna get
听见过不少动物们在那矫情  说什么
a lot of namby-pamby animals in here saying things like,
直播
"我不在乎输赢
"Oh, it's not winning.
重在参与"
It's the taking part that counts."
得了吧伙计  别代表我  我就是来赢的
Yeah, yeah. Not me, pal. I'm here to win.
这奖金我赢定了
That prize, it's mine.
♪People say "Yo Humpty"♪
Digital Underground - "The Humpty Dance"
♪You're really funny lookin'♪
♪That's all right, 'cause I get things cookin'♪
♪Workin' 9 to 5♪
Dolly Parton - "9 To 5"
Men Without Hats - "The Safety Dance"
♪We can dance if we want to♪
♪Aserejè ja♪
Las Ketchup - "Aserejé"
♪de jè de jebe tu de...♪
Christopher Cross - "Ride Like The Wind"
♪Ride like the wind♪
♪Ben,the two of us need look no more♪
Michael Jackson - "Ben"
♪This ain't love, it's clear to see♪
Sam Smith - "Stay With Me"
♪But darling, stay with me♪
谢谢  乔尼
Thank you, Johnny.
好了  下一个
Okay, next up,
-有请米娜  -祝你好运
- We have meena. - Good luck out there.
没事的  来吧  加油  你可以的
All right, come on. Here we go. Come on, you can do it.
你可以的
You can do it. Okay...
对...对不起
Oh, I'm s... Oh, I'm sorry. Uh...
好了  没关系  你不要紧张
Okay. Hey, it's all right. You know, it's all right.
唱吧  米娜
Take it away, Meena.
好吧
Okay.
可以开始了
Anytime, now.
你想从头开始吗
Do you want to start over?
好了  够了
All right, enough of that.
你呆愣了多半天了
That's quite enough of that.
好了  挪挪地儿
That's it. Come on.
下去  大胖妞
Off the stage, Helga.
走吧  你个废物  谢谢
Go on. You're useless. Thanks.
好了  开始吧  音乐起
Right. Here we go. Hit it!
♪Every time it rains,it rains♪
Bing Crosby - "Pennies From Heaven"
♪Pennies from heaven♪
♪Don't you know each cloud contains♪
♪You just gotta ignite the light♪
♪and let it shine♪
♪Just own the night♪
♪like the 4th of July♪
♪'Cause, baby, you're a firework♪
好了  所有人都表演完了  穆恩先生
Okay, that's everyone, Mr. Moon.
好  叫所有人回到台上  克劳利夫人
All right, call everyone back to stage, miss crawly,
现在开始
and let's get...
大家好
Hello!
请各位都上台来  好吗
can I have everybody back to stage, please?
所有人都回到舞台上  等候挑选
Everyone come back to stage for selection.
谢谢  克劳利夫人
Okay. Thank you, Miss Crawly.
不客气  穆恩先生
You're welcome, Mr. Moon.
好了
All right.
我们看看
Let's see, now.
我会选
I'll take...
-你们  -太棒了
- You guys. - Yes!
你们俩谁是女孩
And which one of you is the girl?
呵呵太好笑了
Ha ha. Very funny.
"声音很大很吓人  不过颇有潜质"
"Loud and horrible, but shows promise."
欢迎参加演出
Welcome to the show.
棒  看来我们留下了
Cool. I guess we could hang.
不  不  我只留她  不要你
No, no. I just want her, not you.
什么
What?
好了  合唱组剩下的人
All right, the rest of the group acts,
非常感谢你们的参与
thank you so much.
别难过  伙计们
Oh, don't feel bad, folks.
你们所有人都可以享受
There will be a ten percent discount
购票九折优惠
on tickets for everyone.
得了吧  谢你全家
Yeah, sure, thanks a lot.
咱们走  艾什
Let's get out of here, ash.
艾什
Ash?
好
yeah...
好  咱们走
Yeah, let's go.
独唱组
Okay, soloists.
乔尼  麦克  皮特  理查德
Johnny, Mike, Pete, Richard,
丹尼尔和雷
Daniel and Ray.
麦克
Mike!
这比赛可不能少了你
I've gotta have you in my show.
那我就不客气了
Oh, I... if you insist.
我选皮特
And I'll take Pete...
太好了
Ooh, yeah!
还剩一个
And one more.
我看看
Let me see, now.
我的天啊  对不起
Oh, my gosh, I am so sorry.
我这是怎么了
Oh, what is wrong with me?
感谢参与  理查德
Um, thanks for coming, Richard.
天啊  雷
Oh, my... ray!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
坚持住  雷  我来救你
Just hang in there, ray. I got you.
好了  那么我选的是...
Okay, then I'll take...
丹尼尔  谢谢你  乔尼
Daniel. Thank you, Johnny.
丹尼尔  能听见我说话吗
Daniel, can you hear me?
你入选了
You're in the show!
什么
What?
你在和我说话吗
Are you talking to me?
没错
Yes.
我是说  你入...
I was saying that you are in...
老天  我早晚得喊疯了
Oh, geez, this is gonna drive me nuts.
乔尼  回来  你入选了
Johnny, get back here. You're in.
谢谢你  丹尼尔  再见
Thank you, Daniel. Good-bye.
好耶
Yes!
好了  我就选这些人了
Okay. That's everyone on my list.
等一下
Um, wait a second.
萝丝塔
Rosita.
-萝丝塔还在吗  -在
- Is Rosita still here? - Oh, yes.
我在这里
Yes, I'm here.
萝丝塔  萝丝塔  萝丝塔
Rosita, Rosita, Rosita.
有副好嗓子  但台风相当呆板
Great set of pipes, but boring to watch.
我就知道
I knew it.
所以我该怎么做
So, what should I do?
我可以让你和甘特成为搭档
I could partner you up with Gunter.
甘特  你在哪
Gunter! Where are you?
我在这呢
This is me.
你俩搭档登台一定能擦出火花
It's gonna spice things up on stage.
等等  你想让我们合唱
Wait. You want us to sing together?
我俩一起  可了不得啊
The two of us together, you joking me?
我们一定会嗨翻全场对吧
We're going to be spicy, no?
那考拉瞎了眼  雪莉·安
That koala's a fool, Sherry Anne.
你将来一定会成为大明星
You are going to be a star one day!
海选结束了  兄弟
Auditions are over, pal.
阵容已经选定了
Show's already been cast.
好了  你们都是我选中的人
Okay... You are my chosen few.
太好了
Yes!
是时候了  伙计们
This is it, folks.
我们人生中的决定性时刻到了
A defining moment in all of our lives.
不不不  不是说你们
Um, no. No, no, no, not you guys.
合唱组面试已经结束了
I dismissed all of the group acts already.
你们可以回去了
You... you can go home.
能参与这个节目我们感到非常幸福
我々はこのショーでやることはとても幸せです.
听着  真的很抱歉
Look, I-I'm really sorry,
但人员都招满了
but all of the slots are filled.
我们再为你唱一遍
我々は再びあなたのために歌います!
♪きらきらキラー♪
不不不  听好了
No, no, no, no, listen.
♪ハッピーハッピーハッピー♪
没戏
No in show.
♪未来はほら♪
拜拜各位
Good-bye-bye.
克劳利夫人
Miss Crawly!
行了你们  赶紧出去  出去
Come on, you guys, out... out of here.
快点  下台去  非常感谢
Come on, off the stage. Thank you so much.
穆恩  你这钱有什么说法
Hey, Moon. What's the story?
这箱子里真有奖金吗
Is the prize really inside this thing?
奖金  当然
The prize? Oh, sure.
都在箱子里
Yes, it's all... It's all in there.
打开让我们看看呗
Well, open it, will you?
我想看看十万块的样子
I want to see what $100,000 looks like.
我也想看
Yeah, come on.
是啊  打开箱子吧  穆恩先生
Yeah, yeah, go on. Open it, Mr. Moon.
好吧  我来打开
For sure, I'll open it.
等等  你刚说什么
Wait. What did you say?
他说十万块
He said $100,000.
十万...
A hundr...
我忘带钥匙了
I forgot my keys.
考拉去去就回
Koala be right back.
最后说一遍  克劳利夫人
For the last time, miss Crawly,
我不会解雇你的
I'm not going to fire you.
所以能请你别哭了吗
Now, would you pull yourself together,
还有把鼻涕擤干净
and please blow that nose of yours.
不不  别在这擤
No, no, no, not in here.
-去外面  -抱歉  穆恩先生
- Blow it outside. - I'm sorry, Mr. Moon.
-谢谢你  -巴斯特  你还指望什么
- Thank you. - Buster, what do you expect?
-她快老得没牙了  -艾迪  拜托
- She's like 200 years old. - Eddie, please, look.
如果你们家能借我点钱撑过...
If-if your folks could just loan me the money until...
十万块  巴斯特  醒醒吧
$100,000? Buster, come on.
我想想  我想想  我想想
Hoo! I gotta think. I've gotta think. I've gotta think.
我必须想个办法
I've got to come up with a solution...
也许你该别再胡思乱想
Look, maybe it's time to stop thinking
寻找其他追求了
and it's time to just move on.
你看你这家剧院
I mean, this theater of yours,
可以卖一大笔钱  然后...
you could get some decent money for it and...
也许我们可以一起做些事
I don't know, maybe we could do something together.
做什么  宅在一起打游戏吗
What? What, sit around playing video games?
你知道那是什么吗
Do you know what that is?
一只桶
Uh, it's a bucket?
没错  你知道我为什么留着这桶吗
Yes, and do you know why I have this bucket?
因为房顶漏水吗
'Cause the roof is leaking?
不  那才是接漏水的桶
No, that's the bucket for the leak.
我留着它  因为这是我父亲的桶
I have this one 'cause it belonged to my father.
整整三十年
Every day for 30 years,
他每天都拼死拼活地洗车
he worked his tail off washing cars
只为攒钱给我买下这剧院
just so I could buy this place.
天天如此啊  艾迪
Every day, Eddie.
就为了我
Just for me.
听上去真是个好爸爸
Sounds like a great dad.
所以这事你打算怎么办
So, how do you want to handle this?
穆恩先生  银行的朱迪斯又打来了
Oh, Mr. Moon, I got Judith from the bank
我转到2号线了
holding on line two again.
看来我只有一条路可走了
Well, there's only one thing I can do.
大家都听好了
Okay, everybody, listen up.
我要你们都回家  马上
I gotta send you all home. Right now.
什么
What?
没错
Yep.
因为我父亲以前常说
'Cause, like my dad used to say,
"睡个好觉才能更好地工作"
"Get a good night's sleep and do a great day's work."
说的没错
That's right.
明天一早我们就开始彩排
Rehearsals begin first thing tomorrow morning.
如果你们想成为明星  赢十万大奖
And if you want to become stars and win 100 grand,
那你们最好拿出前所未有的劲头
then you better be ready to work harder
加倍努力地练习
than you've ever worked in your lives.
所以好好睡一觉  去追寻伟大梦想吧
So get some sleep and dream big dreams.
♪きらきらキラー♪
♪ハッピーハッピーハッピー♪
克劳利夫人
Miss Crawly!
♪未来はほら♪
好了  走吧  够了
Okay, come on. That's enough now.
♪ラッキーラッキーラッキー♪
快点  都下台去
Come on, off the stage. Please.
-追寻伟大梦想  -说得很好吧
- Dream big dreams? - I know, it's good, right?
上哪找十万块奖金啊
What about the 100 grand?
不用担心  艾迪
Don't you worry, Eddie.
总会有办法的
There's got to be a way to get it.
什么  巴斯特  不  听我说
What? Buster, no, listen to me!
这场演出无法挽救你的剧院
This show is not gonna save your theater.
你都跌到谷底了  老兄
You're at rock bottom, pal.
没错  你知道身陷谷底
Yep, and you know what's great
最棒的是什么吗  艾迪
about hitting rock bottom, Eddie?
只剩下一个方向可走了
There's only one way left to go,
就是向上
and that's up.
幸运入选者
大家可以看到  幸运的入选者正离开剧院
And you can see the lucky few leaving the theater behind me.
现在交还给演播室  约翰
Now back to you in the studio, John.
亲爱的  别伤心了
Oh, honey, please don't cry.
你没失败
You are not a failure.
还会有其他机会的
There'll be other chances.
-你只要...  -得了吧  会有个鬼
- You just... - Bah! The heck there will!
爸爸  别这样
Dad, please.
拜托  你不想上台表演吗
Come on! Don't you want this?
当然想  但我搞砸了
Well, sure, but I messed it up.
那明天就再回去  告诉他
Then you gotta go back there tomorrow and say,
"穆恩先生  我强烈要求再试一次"
"Mr. Moon, I demand you let me re-audition!"
有点自信  向他们证明你是有本事的
Be confident! Show 'em you ain't gonna be pushed around!
懂了吗  米娜
You got that, Meena?
很好
Good!
去帮我拿可可
Now, go get my cocoa.
我不向任何人折腰
I won't sell out for nobody
我不与傻子同台
Won't follow no fool.
别唱了行吗  我这么做都是为了我俩
Would you stop? I'd only be doing it for us.
真的吗
Oh, really?
当然是真的
Yes, really.
如果我赢了那些钱  我们就可以
If I won that money, we could build
拥有自己的录音棚  开创我们自己的牌子
our own recording studio, start our own label.
这样全世界都能听到你的歌声
I mean, the whole world would get to hear your songs.
我才不听我马子瞎扯
I'm not listening to my girlfriend
她就是想出去卖
Cause she just want to sell out...
请等一下
Hey! Uh, just a min...
等等  等等
Oh, oh, wait. W-wait!
瞧啊
Oh, look at...
我认识德里克  那个经理
I know Derek, the manager.
他会为我担保  拜托
He'll vouch for me. Come on!
马里奥
Hey, Mario.
最近咋样啊
How's it going?
有没有搞错
Oh, for crying out loud.
行啊  狗熊都能进
Oh, yeah, oh, let the bears in.
狗熊都能进  你厉害
Let the bears in. Fine.
他来了
There he is!
有个惊喜给你  儿子
I got a surprise for you, my son.
什么惊喜
What's that?
-告诉他计划  -好
- Tell him the plan. - Right.
我们听说有艘运载了2500万黄金的船
We've been told there's a ship carrying 25 million in gold,
今晚会停靠在这里的码头
gonna dock at night right here.
警卫和往常一样守在这里  还有这里
With the usual guards here and here.
不过我们命好  这正好有个下水道
But, lucky for us, there's a sewer right under here.
所以接应的车和我们在这碰头
So the getaway driver meets us here.
这次由你来开车  乔尼
And that is gonna be you this time, Johnny.
-什么  你要我来开车  -是的
- What? You want... You want me to drive? - Yeah.
我儿子也该在咱们帮里独当一面了
It's time my boy had a proper role in the gang, eh?
等下  等下  爸爸
Hang on, hang on, dad.
我们的司机一直是巴里
Barry's always been our driver.
巴里不会介意的
Barry don't mind.
对吧  巴里
Do you, Barry?
-不  我不介意  -就是
- No. No, that's fine. - Yeah.
所以  那艘船具体什么时候入港
So... so, when exactly is this ship coming in, then?
精确时间我们还不清楚
We ain't got a date yet.
这两天应该到不了吧
Probably won't be for a while, though, will it?
你担心啥  这是我们干的最后一票
What do you care? It's the last job we ever need to do.
一得手我们就远走高飞
When it comes in, we go.
明白吗
Right?
太好了
Great.
我等不及了
Can't wait.
您好  我看见你在报上登的广告
Hi. I saw your ad in the paper.
是的  我需要保姆帮我看几个星期的孩子
Yes, I need a nanny just for a couple of weeks.
可以吗  太好了
You can? Great.
孩子们吗
Oh, the kids?
他们超乖的
Yes, they're wonderful.
他们...  是的  我有25个孩子
They... yeah, I have 25.
不  我没开玩笑
No, I'm... I'm not joking.
但他们真的很听话
Um, but they're really no problem...
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
晚安  妈咪
Good night, mommy.
会议开的怎么样
Hey. How was the big meeting?
这么糟糕啊
That bad, really?
我有件激动人心的事要告诉你
Well, I have something really exciting to tell you.
你做的派很好吃  亲爱的
You make the best pie, honey.
听着  诺曼  我知道有些仓促
Listen, Norman, I know it's short notice,
但明天我真得需要人照看下孩子
but I could really use some help with the kids tomorrow
因为  你一定不会相信我今天做了什么
because... well, you are not gonna believe what I did today.
歌唱大赛海选
十万大奖等你拿
诺曼  你有在听吗
Norman, are you listening to me?
明天一早我们就开始彩排
Rehearsals begin first thing tomorrow morning,
所以好好睡一觉  追寻伟大梦想吧
so get some sleep and dream big dreams.
早上好啊  孩子们
Good morning, everybody.
吃早餐前都必须穿戴整齐
Now, I want you all dressed before breakfast.
吃早饭了
Breakfast!
萝丝塔  你看见我车钥匙了吗
Rosita, have you seen my car keys?
别忘了  钥匙在你外套口袋里
Don't forget, your keys are in your coat pocket.
我找到了
Oh, I found 'em.
-再见  亲爱的  -再见  诺曼
- Bye, honey. - Bye, Norman.
该上学了
Time for school.
再见伊吉  再见佩里  再见卡拉
Bye, Iggy. Bye, Perry. Bye, Carla.
再见盖尔  再见罗利  再见米奇
Bye, Gail. Bye, Rory. Bye, Mickey.
再见莫伊  再见尼尔森  再见汉娜
Bye, Moe. Bye, Nelson. Bye, Hannah.
再见泰斯  再见凯利  再见乔治
Bye, Tess. Bye, Kelly. Bye, George.
再见安迪 再见弗雷迪  再见卡斯帕
Bye, Andy. Bye, Freddy. Bye-bye, Caspar.
闭馆彩排
这场比赛就是战争
This contest is war.
这个舞台就是战场
This stage is the battlefield.
你们的歌曲就是武器
Your song is your weapon.
你们只有一次机会惊艳观众
Now, you only get one shot to blow that audience away,
所以请从我为你们量身定制的歌单上
so choose carefully from the list of songs
慎重选择参赛歌曲
I've selected for each of you.
看来做通你男朋友的工作了
Ah, talked some sense into that boyfriend of yours.
兰斯是个艺术家
Lance is an artist,
但我也没指望你能理解
but I wouldn't expect you to understand that.
你说对了  我完全不理解
You're right. I don't understand that at all.
你们会注意到我在每张歌单上都注明了
Now, you'll notice each list also includes my costume
着装和表演建议
and performance suggestions.
好吗  克劳利夫人会带你们去彩排室
Okay? Miss Crawly will show you to your rehearsal spaces.
我们开工吧
Now, let's get to work.
打扰一下  穆恩先生
Excuse me, Mr. Moon?
我的纸上写着
For some reason, it says here
我需要弹钢琴
that I should be playing the piano?
没错  试想一下  像你这样深情的大高个
Yes, just imagine-- big, soulful guy like you
柔情款款轻抚琴键
tenderly playing the keys.
所有人都会为你倾倒
There'll be goose bumps everywhere.
可我很久都没弹钢琴了
Well, I haven't played piano since I was a kid.
克劳利夫人  给这位上几节钢琴课
Miss Crawly, we're gonna need some piano lessons over here.
好的  先生  请上楼  我一会儿就来
Yes, sir! Up the stairs. I'll be right along.
还有皮特  你在这里练习
And, Pete, you're in here.
没问题  穆恩先生
You got it, Mr. Moon.
自省一下吧  老兄
Check your ego, man.
-冷静点  冷静点  -是吗
- Break it up, break it up, break it up. - Oh, yeah?
让瑞奇冷静去吧  他起头的
Tell Ricki. He started it.
没错  也是我起头成立了这乐队
That's right. Just like I started this band.
我的乐队  豪伊
My band, Howie.
恕臣失礼了  起头殿下
Oh, forgive me, your highness.
伙计们  别吵了
Guys, come on.
不不不  出去  赶紧出去
No, no, no, no, no. Hey, hey. Out. Get out of here.
听着  都冷静下来
Look, just calm down
赶紧挑首歌吧
and pick a song.
我觉得我们要想赢下比赛的话
I think we'll probably have a better chance of winning
最好我负责唱歌
if I do the singing part
你负责跳舞
and leave the dancing part to you.
不要  你开玩笑吗
Bah. Are you joking me?
你只是缺一场火辣热身而已
You are just in need of, like, a super cool warm-up.
来吧   让我们把衣服都脱了
Come on, let's take off these clothes.
没这个必要吧
That... that is not necessary.
太暴露了
That is a lot of skin.
别愁眉苦脸的
Ah, don't you look so worried face.
我也给你准备了一件
I've got one for you, too.
肥仔
Hey, porky!
-小声点行吗  -抱歉
- Keep it down, will you? - Sorry.
穆恩  你发错歌单了
Hey, Moon, you gave me the wrong list.
低俗的流行乐不是我的风格
Cheesy pop's not exactly my style.
风格  我很高兴你说起了风格
Style. I'm glad you brought that up.
我们来瞧瞧
Now, let's see.
这个
There.
这颜色是不是很配你
Isn't this a great color for you?
看不出来  我眼睛快被辣瞎了
I can't tell. It's melting my eyes.
-你有黑色的衣服吗  -黑色
- You got anything in black? - Black?
怎么  你想让观众以为你是去参加葬礼吗
What, you want everyone to think you're going to a funeral?
你以为你是格调高雅的艺术家吗
You think you're some kind of artsy-fartsy type?
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
有了  流行小天后裙
Bingo! Pop star Princess!
这也是比赛的一部分吗
Is this part of the competition?
好了  大家别惊慌
Okay, everybody, don't panic.
-别惊慌  -发生什么事了
- Don't panic. - What's going on?
说句话呀  克劳利
Talk to me, Crawly.
你上次付电费是什么时候  穆恩先生
When did we last pay the power company, Mr. Moon?
老天爷啊
Oh, for Pete's sake.
好了  别担心  各位
Okay, don't worry, everybody.
我来想办法搞定
I will take care of this.
与此同时  你们摸着黑继续彩排
In the meantime, you will continue to rehearse in the dark.
-什么  -可我什么都看不见
- What? - But I can't see anything.
不必担心  萝丝塔
Don't you worry, Rosita.
我有荧光棒
I have glow sticks.
很好  正好趁这个机会
Great. Use this time to shake off
甩掉第一天的拘束情绪  我去去就回
those first-day inhibitions, and I'll be right back.
-你在逗我吗  -你们听到了
- You gotta be kidding me. - Okay, you heard him.
都回去排练
Back to work now.
去吧  各位
Come on, everybody.
抱歉   老朋友  我会修好的
Sorry, old girl. I'll fix that.
穆恩先生
Mr. Moon?
你可能不记得我了
You-you probably don't remember me,
但我昨天参加了海选  而且我...
but I-I auditioned yesterday, and I...
听着
Hey, listen.
你觉得你能够到那平台吗
Do you think maybe you could reach the ledge?
那个平台吗
Th-that ledge?
你的鼻子还真有两把刷子
Whoa, that's a heck of a trunk you've got there.
非常感谢  孩子
Thanks a lot, kid.
穆恩先生
Uh, Mr. Moon?
我叫米娜  我为你烤了个蛋糕
M-my name is Meena, and I baked a cake for you,
还有...  我在想你能不能
and, uh... uh, I was wondering if you'd maybe give me
-再给我一次机会...  -稍等一下
- a second chance to... - Just a moment, please.
马上就来
Be right with you.
太好了  终于来电了
Yay! It's about time.
乔尼
Johnny...
当心别磕到头
Yep, mind your head here.
你能拉下幕布绳吗
Hey, can you pull up that scenic cable?
-你说这条  -没错  就是那个
- You mean this? - Yes, that's it.
太棒了
Great!
室内灯光
还有室内灯光
And the house lights?
我知道  太美了对吧
Ah, I know. Beautiful, isn't she?
话说  孩子
You know what, kid?
你也来参加这场演出怎么样
How would you like to be a part of this show?
真的吗  等等
Really? Wait.
天啊  我还正准备问你来着
Oh, my gosh, I was just gonna ask about that.
太好了  因为我急需一名舞台管理员
Great. 'Cause I could really use a stagehand.
舞台管理员
Stagehand?
-可是...  -不用担心
- But... - Ah, don't worry about it.
你很快就能上手
You're gonna pick it up in no time.
我全都教给你  跟我来
I'll teach you everything I know. Follow me.
这边是练习室和化妆室
These are the rehearsal spaces and dressing rooms,
楼上是创作室和办公室
and up here we got workshops and the main office.
向上
Up in the air!
摸脚趾
Touch your toes!
真棒
Awesome.
还棒
Awesome?
我看你想说的是"棒槌"吧
Yeah, I think the word you're after is "Awful."
用这词都算给他们面子了
And that's me restraining myself.
这些家伙根本毫无天赋
There's not an ounce of talent between 'em.
丁点没有  其实你知道吗
Not an ounce. In fact, you know what?
那奖金我十拿九稳了
I think that prize is as good as mine already.
银行
没错  我很快就会有
Yes, indeed, uh, I am about to come
非常非常大的一笔钱入账了
into a very, very large sum of money.
准确地说是十万块
$100,000, to be precise.
是这样啊
Well, is that so?
那样的话  先生  你会需要我们的白金卡
In that case, sir, you'll be wanting our platinum card.
瞧瞧  又见面了
Well, well, well, hello again.
老天  这些歌简直是烂到家了
Oh, man, these are, like, the cheesiest songs of all time.
我知道  对吧
I know, right?
我甚至想自己写首歌来着
I mean, I was even thinking of writing my own song instead.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
-你自己写歌  -没错
- Your own song? - Well, yeah.
听着  如果你想赢得奖金
Look, if you want to win that money,
就照考拉说的做
just do what the koala says.
怎么  你觉得我写不出歌吗
Why? You think I can't write my own song?
别激动  我就这么一说
Whoa, whoa. I'm just saying,
不是每个人都能写歌的
not everyone can write songs, okay?
我知道我写歌貌似很轻松  宝贝
I know I make it look easy, babe,
但其实不容易
but it's not.
她回来了
Oh, here she is.
安静一点  各位
Quiet down, everybody.
米娜  你入选了吗
So, Meena, are you in the show?
是的  算是吧...
Uh... well, yeah, kind of, but...
加油米娜  我们爱米娜
她做到了
She did it!
我真为你骄傲  我简直快乐炸了
Oh, I'm so proud of you, I could pop!
我生日愿望总算成真了
That's my birthday wish coming true right there!
-你太棒了  米娜  -米娜  我们爱你
- Way to go, Meena! - Oh, Meena, we love you!
妈妈
Mom...
我们爱米娜
-怎么回事  -等下  等下
- What the heck? - Wait a minute, wait a minute.
别生气好吗  是你外婆说的
Don't be mad, okay? It was your grandma.
她让整条街都知道你参加海选去了
She told the whole street about your audition.
-妈妈  不  等等  -别说话  宝贝
- Mom, no, wait. - Shh, shh. Shush, baby.
你得好好保养你的金嗓子
You need to save that singing voice of yours.
所以从现在开始
So, from now on,
只用点头摇头  明白吗
just nod or shake your head, okay?
怎么样  老爸
How was that, dad?
你转弯的时候太慢了  乔尼
You're still too soft on them corners, Johnny.
你得再强硬些
You got to attack 'em.
而且车被你开得嘎吱响
And you're crunching the gears.
我说过  你必须轻轻地...
I told you, you got to be gentle with the...
把音乐关掉
Look, turn that down.
你爹跟你说话呢
Listen to your father!
"转弯的时候太慢了  乔尼"
"Too soft on the corners, Johnny."
"你这样做不行  乔尼"
"You're not doing it right, Johnny."
"再快点  乔尼"
"Speed up, Johnny."
"按我这样开"
"Do it like I showed you."
老爸
Dad?
糟了  我从老爸身上碾过去了
Oh, no. I've run over my dad.
这样才像话
Now, that is more like it.
"从此以后  三只小猪"
"And the three little pigs..."
"幸福地生活着"
"lived happily ever after."
"晚安  宝贝们"
"Good night, my dears."
诺曼  你还醒着吗
Norman, are you awake?
你今天怎么样  亲爱的
How was your day, honey?
老样子
Same as always.
-是吗  -是的
- It was? - Mm-hmm.
我不知道你怎么做到的  亲爱的
I don't know how you do it all, honey.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
各位来宾  大小动物们
All creatures great and small,
欢迎来到穆恩剧院
welcome to the moon theater!
穆恩先生
Mr. Moon?
-银行的朱迪斯要找您  -什么
- I have Judith from the bank. - What?
不  不  不  告诉她我明早给她回电话
Whoa, no, no, no. Tell her I'll call her back in the morning.
不行啊
Oh, I can't.
她已经到了
She's right here.
朱迪斯  你好
Judith! Hello.
我们是开银行的  不是做慈善的
I work for a bank, not a charity,
如果到了月底你的账户
and if your accounts are not settled
-还没有足够的资金  -好吧  朱迪斯
- by the end of the month... - Okay, Judith...
我以个人名义担保  到本月末
I personally guarantee, by the end of this month,
这场演出将会取得
this show is going to be
前所未见的巨大成功
the biggest hit this city has ever seen.
穆恩先生  你的演出从来没成功过
Mr. Moon, none of your shows have ever worked.
一个都没有
None of them!
你曾有过机会
You've had your chances.
现在把你的账户结清吧
Now, settle your accounts,
否则我们要收回剧院所有权
or we will repossess this property.
好的  再见了您呐
Okay. Toodle-oo.
你要怎么办啊  穆恩先生
What are you going to do, Mr. Moon?
老实说
Honestly,
我不知道
I have no idea.
♪I listen to the wind♪
♪to the wind of my soul♪
♪Where I'll end up well I think, only God really knows♪
♪I've sat upon the...♪
你穿的是泳衣吗  艾迪
Are you wearing a speedo, Eddie?
你  你干什么...
What... what are you...?
艾迪  一切都还好吧
Eddie? Is everything all right?
都好  我就是游个泳  妈妈
Yeah, just doing my laps, ma!
你现在是住在泳池小屋里吗
So, what, you live in the pool house now?
是的  我的家人希望我更加...
Yeah, my folks want me to be more,
我猜是更独立吧
you know, independent, I guess.
他们甚至给我约了个人生导师
They even hooked me up with this life coach dude.
-人生导师  -是
- Life coach? - Yeah.
我猜是要他帮我发现人生的目标
I guess he's gonna help me find my purpose in life.
我以为我有目标了  但是最后
I thought I had one, but it turns out
发现不适合我什么的  我也不知道
it wasn't the right one or something. I don't know.
总之  他给我安排了一个日程表
Anyway, he's got me on this whole schedule thing.
比如说  周一  倒垃圾
It's, like, mondays, take out the recycling;
周二  修剪草坪  周三  拜访娜奶奶
Tuesdays, mow the lawn; Wednesdays, go visit Nana;
周四  清理泳池
Thursdays, clean the pool.
这些事我们不是雇了人来做了吗
It's like, don't we have people to do all of this stuff?
你等等  等一下
Whoa, whoa. Back up.
你家娜奶奶还活着
Your Nana is still alive?
当然
Oh, yeah..
她还很有钱  对吧
And she's rich, right?
简直富得流油
She's loaded.
但是相信我  你绝对不会想靠近她
But trust me, you don't want to go near my Nana.
她的脾气可大得很
She is one mean sheep.
♪There may be trouble ahead♪
♪But while there's moonlight♪
♪And music and love and romance♪
把灯光调暗
Fade the spot.
♪Music and dance♪
很好  把月亮放下来
Good. Lower the moon.
-咖啡  -谢谢  克劳利夫人
- Coffee? - Thank you, Miss Crawly.
这东西经常这样
Okay, that's normal.
只需要敲一下就行
Just needs a knock.
瞧  你已经上手了
See? You're getting it.
♪While we still got the chance♪
谁看见我的玻璃眼珠了
Anyone seen my glass eye?
这个鬼东西老是掉出来
The darn thing keeps popping out.
你差点害死我  大块头
You almost killed me, jumbo!
-不是我  -是吗
- It wasn't me. - Is that so?
皮特
Pete?
Pete!
你会没事的  放心吧  只要
You're gonna be all right. Okay, just...
你坚持住  伙计
just hang in there, buddy.
里奇  凯
Ricki? Kai?
你们怎么不排练了
Why aren't you guys rehearsing?
我们退出
We're through.
他们说我是个让人受不了的超级自大狂
They said I'm an intolerable egomaniac.
我都不知道那是什么意思
I don't even know what that means.
好吧  我们一下少了两个节目
All right. We're two acts down.
给我点好消息吧  克劳利夫人
Give me some good news, Miss Crawly.
其实没有看起来那么糟
It's not as bad as it looks.
哎呀
Oopsie-Daisy.
米娜  你愿意再来一次面试吗
Meena, how would you like to re-audition for the show?
真的吗  当然啦
Really? Well, yeah.
-太棒了  -我是说  不
- Great. - I mean, no.
什么
What?
我是说  是的  我会唱
I-I mean, yes, I can sing.
但是  不行  我会紧张的  我做不来
But no, I...I get so nervous, and... I...I can't do it.
我是说我可以唱  但是  不行  我不行
I mean, I would totally do it, but... no, I... no.
我就当你是答应了
I'm gonna take that as a maybe.
很好  你看  她们回来了
Great! Look, they're back.
我们一会儿再谈  米娜
We're gonna come back to this, Meena.
听着几位  忘了我之前说的吧
Listen, guys, forget what I said before.
你们都很有才华
You are very talented.
请你们  来参加演出  好吗
Please, join the show, okay?
好吗  不行吗
Yes? No?
这里
Here.
你们恶臭得像脚趾甲
足の爪のように臭い.
什么  不  不  等等  等一下
What? No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
不要走  别走
D-don't go, don't go!
这是做什么
What is this for?
我们用这个来记住步伐
Now, we use this to follow the steps.
♪Goddess on the mountain top♪
♪Burning like a silver flame♪
♪The summit of beauty and love♪
卡斯帕  卡斯帕  不要
Caspar! Caspar, no!
这下可好啦
How about this?
我怎么跟你说的
Come on. What did I tell you?
很抱歉  他发烧了
I'm so sorry. He had a fever,
叫保姆又来不及了  所以
and it was too late to get a sitter, so...
看来你一点病都没有啊
Well, you seem fine now.
♪I'm your Venus♪
♪I'm your fire♪
都被你弄乱了
You're messiong it up!
我是不会唱这个的
I am not singing this.
为啥不喜欢啊
What's not to like?
你是女的  又是个青少年
You're a female, and you're a teenager.
这歌就是写给你们的
This song was made for you.
我的少女小心思都被你看透透了
It's like you can see inside my tiny teenage mind.
厉害吧  你只需要多跳几步
I know, right? You just gotta add some moves
再来一点...
and a little bit of...
♪Hey I just met you♪
♪and this is crazy♪
♪But here's my number♪
♪So Call Me Maybe♪
-去吧  -你是指这样吗
- Go for it! - You mean like this?
♪Try to chase me♪
♪But here's my number♪
♪So Call Me Maybe♪
这就对了  你真是一点就通
There you go. You're a natural.
是的  难听死了
Yes, that was very bad.
乔尼
Johnny.
快回话  完毕
Come in. Over.
乔尼  你的夹克在说话
Johnny, your jacket's talking.
乔尼  你在哪里
Johnny, where are you?
老爸  怎么了  完毕
Dad, what's going on? Over.
你现在要走是什么意思
What do you mean, you gotta leave now?
我知道  我真的很抱歉
I know. I'm... I'm so sorry.
只不过我家里有事需要我过去
It's just, I've got this family business thing.
你是不是对这场演出
Do I need to start worrying
还三心二意啊  乔尼
about your commitment here, Johnny?
-请说没有  -没有  绝对没有
- Tell me no. - No. Absolutely not.
我保证不会有下次了
I promise it won't happen again.
-最好没有  -谢谢  穆恩先生
- It better not. - Thank you, Mr. Moon.
亲爱的  我回来了
Baby, I'm back.
♪I want love to♪
♪Change my friends to enemies♪
这是怎么回事
What is going on here?
你好  我是贝琪
Hi. I'm Becky.
贝琪
Becky?
你还指望怎么样
What did you expect?
你总是不在我身边
You're never around anymore.
我这么做是为了我们俩  兰斯
I did it for us, Lance!
你和我
You and me!
亲爱的  对不起
Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry.
我把太阳镜落在里面了
I think I left my sunglasses in there.
来吧  贝琪
Come on, Becky.
我们走
Let's get out of here.
赢大钱了  宝贝儿
Jackpot, baby!
好了  我觉得今晚就到这里吧  伙计们
Well, I say we call it a night there, fellas.
把现金放进我车里好吗  德里克
Put the cash in my car, will you, Derek?
你牌技真高啊  麦克
Well, you're one great card player, Mike.
你也不错啊
Not so bad yourself.
不过我还没弄懂你是怎么出的老千
Except I still can't tell how you cheated.
出千  出千
Cheated? Cheated?
你这是在侮辱我
I am offended.
来吧  宝贝儿  我们还是走吧
Come on, baby, let's cut some rug.
什么
Wh-what the...?
这是怎么跑进去的
How did that get there?
快跑啊  宝贝儿
Run for it, baby!
抓住他
Get him!
请让一下
Excuse me.
别让他跑了
Don't let him get away!
-谢谢  德里克  -快让开
- Thanks, Derek. - Out of the way.
回见了  废球们
So long, suckers!
早上好  巴斯特
Good morning, buster.
-你好  艾迪  你好吗  -很好
- Hey, Eddie. How are you? - Good.
-演出怎么样了  -很顺利
- How's the show going? - It's going great.
你今天的外套很帅气嘛
Hey, that's a sharp jacket you've got on today.
过奖了
Thanks.
等一下
Wait.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
艾迪 你去看娜奶奶的时候
Eddie, you can't come visit your Nana
怎么能不带束花呢
without bringing her some flowers.
-拿着  -什么  不
- Here. - What? No!
巴斯特  不要  不要进去
Buster, no! Don't go in there!
有什么可以帮助...
Yes, can I help...?
-巴斯特  -娜娜啊
- Buster! - Ah, Nana!
看看您  亲爱的娜奶奶
Just look at you, dear.
您一点都不像九十多岁的人
You don't look a day over 90.
我的天哪
Oh, my gosh.
巴斯特·穆恩
Buster Moon.
我们在艾迪的毕业典礼上见过
We met at Eddie's graduation.
我好荣幸啊
Lucky me.
我那废物孙子和他坏透了的
A visit from my useless grandson
捣鼓剧院的朋友来看我了
and his ghastly little theater friend.
看哪  她还记得我
Look at that-- she remembers me.
那好  娜娜
Okay, Nana...
您愿不愿意赞助
How would you like to be the sponsor
一场非常火爆的大奖赛呢
for a very prestigious prize?
如果是新闻上那个歌唱比赛  不愿意
Not for that singing contest I saw on the news.
就是那个
That's the one.
我明白了
I see.
你没钱付奖金  对吧
You don't have the money, do you?
我们的钱全部锁在...
Well, we don't quite have it all locked in...
我是一分钱不会给你的
Well, you'll not get a cent out of me.
娜奶奶  求你了  听我说几句
Nana, please, just listen to me for one second, okay?
不  我不想听你说
No, absolutely not.
-别听他的  奶奶  -等一下
- Don't listen to him, Nana. - Just wait one second.
你俩我都不想听
I'm not listening to either of you.
正山小种红茶  不加糖  快一点
Lapsang souchong, no sugar, and be quick about it.
娜娜  我不会泡茶
Nana, I-I don't know how to make tea.
娜娜·诺多曼
这场演出我从小就看过
I saw this show when I was a kid.
娜娜  您那时真是太惊艳了
Nana, you were absolutely amazing.
省省吧  奉承我也没用
Please, this flattery is futile.
我一点都不想帮你
I have no intention of bailing you out.
你的剧院之所以没观众
Your pathetic shows are the reason
就是因为你排的那些破演出
that theater no longer has an audience.
但是这场演出会把他们全部吸引进去
But this show is gonna... Gonna pack 'em in
就像以前那些美好的日子
like it did in the good old days.
那不只是以前的美好日子  穆恩先生
They were not "good old days," Mr. Moon.
那是宏伟壮丽的时代
They were magnificent.
而你的剧院在那时
And that theater of yours,
是奇迹与魔力的殿堂
it was a palace of wonder and magic.
奶奶  它现在也是
But, Nana, it still is.
是才怪
Yeah, right.
我还能想起穿着天鹅绒正装的引座员
I can recall the ushers in their velvet suits.
买票的队伍排了好远
Queues a mile long just to get a ticket.
壮丽的舞台上幕布缓缓升起
The curtain rising over that glorious stage.
让梦想成真的音乐和灯光渐起
Music and light bringing dreams to life?
正是如此
Precisely.
如今它还是你记忆中的样子
Well, it's just like you remember it.
实际上  我让它变得更加壮观了
In fact, I've made it even more spectacular.
你才没有
No, you haven't.
您自己来看吧
Come see for yourself.
一场为您准备的特别演出
A special performance just for you.
您觉得如何  奶奶
What do you say, Nana?
我觉得
I say...
你就是个骗子  穆恩先生
You are a liar, Mr. Moon.
好了  我们可以走了  谢谢  奶奶
Okay, well, we're done now. Thank you, Nana.
不过也好过和这个老鬼在棋桌前
But anything's better than spending another evening
再下一晚上跳棋了
playing checkers with this old fart.
什么
What?
太棒了
Great.
一定会让你眼界大开的  奶奶
It's gonna blow you away, Nana.
我决不食言
And that is no lie.
听好了
Now, listen up.
明天我们要举行一场完整的试演
Tomorrow we are going to have a full preview of the show,
而我们的观众只有娜娜·诺多曼女士一人
and our audience will be none other than miss Nana noodleman.
-娜娜·诺多曼  -天哪  娜娜·诺多曼
- Nana Noodleman? - Wow, Nana Noodleman.
她还活着呢
She's still alive?
是的  相信我
Oh, yes, and believe me,
她的眼界相当的高
she's got some pretty high standards.
所以  今天  我们要全部
All right? So, today, we're going to have
着装彩排  我希望看到你们
a full dress rehearsal, and I want to see you
点亮这个舞台  伙计们
light up the stage, folks.
-太酷了  -米娜  克劳利夫人
- Well, that's cool. - Meena? Miss Crawly?
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
真是雄心勃勃的
Wow, it's so ambitious.
是啊  你确定吗
Yeah,are you sure about this?
我承诺向娜娜奉献一场盛景
I promised Nana something spectacular,
而这个  一定会让她叹为观止
and this-- ha! It's gonna blow her away.
-是的  -还有两分钟  大伙儿
- Oh, yes. - Two minutes, everybody.
乔尼
Johnny.
乔尼  你在哪里
Johnny, where are you?
乔尼  快点回复对讲机
Johnny, answer the walkie-talkie.
好的  老爸  我在这里
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, dad. I'm here. I'm here.
-怎么了  -来消息了
- What's wrong? - We got the call.
货船来了
Shipment's coming in.
-今天晚上吗  -不是今晚  是现在
- Tonight? - Not tonight. Now.
两分钟后在赫克托街角碰头
Meet us on the corner of Hector street in two minutes.
待在这里
Stay here.
我们37分钟后...
We'll be back in exactly 37...
37分钟  知道啦
Yeah, 37 minutes. Yep.
你已经说了好多次了
You've told me repeatedly.
来得及
I can make it.
唱得好  麦克
Bravo, Mike.
娜娜一定会喜欢的
Nana is gonna love that.
你真是  你真是太客气了  穆恩先生
You're... you're too kind, Mr. Moon.
而且我非常喜欢你的新衣服  先生
And I myself am loving the new suit, sir.
好了  下一位请上台  艾什
Okay, can we see Ash next, please?
艾什  快点上来
Ash, let's get you out here.
大家注意避让
Stand back.
喜怒无常的青少年来了
Moody teenager coming through.
祝你好运  艾什
Good luck, ash.
♪I threw a wish in the well♪
♪Don't ask me I'll never tell♪
♪I looked to you as it fell♪
♪And now you're in my way♪
♪Your old stare was holding ripped jeans skin was showing♪
♪Hot night Wind was blowing♪
♪Where d' you think you're going baby♪
♪Hey I just met you♪
♪And this is crazy♪
♪But here's my number♪
♪So call me maybe♪
哇  哇  哇  好了  够了
Whoa, whoa. Okay, enough of that.
别放了  别放了  关掉
Cut it, cut it, cut it, cut it.
她这样怎么会有人给她打电话
I don't think anyone's gonna call her after that.
好了  艾什
Okay, Ash,
来吧  艾什
Come on, ash.
怎么了  你不喜欢这条裙子吗
What is it? Do you... Do you not like the dress?
艾什  怎么了
Ash, what's wrong?
我觉得吧
Well, it sounds to me like you
你就该趁早离开那个...
are way better off without that... that...
超级无敌大混球
That total super-jerk dinkleschplatt!
正是  超级无敌大混球
Exactly. Total super-jerk dinkleschplatt.
萝丝塔  甘特
Rosita! Gunter!
-下一个该你们了  -好的  给你
- You're on next. - Yeah, okay, here.
这里面应该有口香糖或者糖果什么的
There should be some gum or some candy in there somewhere.
你自己拿吧  别客气
Just help yourself.
萝丝塔  萝丝塔  萝丝塔
Rosita, Rosita, Rosita.
等等  等等  等一下
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
我能插个队吗
Can I take your place, please?
-好的乔尼  去吧  -好的  准备好
- Sure, Johnny. Go ahead. - Okay, get ready,
我警告你
'cause I'm warning you...
我要用我的猪猪力量震爆整个舞台
This stage is about to explode with major piggy power.
很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我也没办法
I have no control.
好的  来吧  你可以的
Okay, come on, you can do this.
♪I stay out too late♪
♪Got nothing in my brain♪
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我很好  谢谢关心
Yes, I'm fine, thank you.
-你好吗  -好吧
- How are you? - Okay.
乔尼  快出来吧
Johnny, let's get you out here!
伙计们  你们还得加强练习舞步
And, you guys, you've gotta work on that routine.
开始表演吧  乔尼
Take it away, Johnny!
♪What would I do without your smart mouth♪
♪Drawing me in, and you kicking me out♪
♪Got my head spinning...♪
你不能只是唱歌
You can't just sing it.
你得表现出你的热情和渴望
You've got to show the fire und desire.
热情早就没有了
The fire went out a long time ago.
什么
What?
你看  我甚至记不住那些步伐
Look, I can't even keep count of the steps.
步伐有什么好记的
Ugh! Counting schmounting!
她唱歌总是想得太多  对吧
She sings too much with her head, right?
没错吧
Ja, ja, see?
不要刻意去记舞步
Forget the steps and just, like,
让音乐自然而然地带动你的关节
let the music take control of your body parts.
可我的身体根本不听使唤
My body parts are not responding, okay?
我真的做不到
It's never gonna happen.
我还是先去买菜吧
I should just be getting groceries.
-萝丝塔  别走  -萝丝塔  别这样
- Rosita, no. -Rosita, come on.
萝丝塔  别这样  别走啊
What? Rosita, please. Like, don't go.
我在下面
Down here.
你有看到三只长相凶恶的大狗熊吗
Have you seen three nasty-looking bears out there?
没有
No.
那就好  顺带说一下  我喜欢你的表演
Great.  by the way, I love your act.
说真的  你摔得猪啃泥那一下
Seriously, the... the part where you fall flat on your face?
每次想起来都能笑死我
That... That cracks me up, every time.
回见啦  肥猪姐
See you around, porky.
♪And you give me all of you♪
老天
Man.
乔尼  我知道我要求有点高
Johnny,  I know I'm asking a lot of you...
穆恩先生  我真的努力了  我发誓
Mr. Moon, I'm really trying, I promise.
那你的备选歌曲呢
What about your backup song?
你有练习过吗
Have you practiced that?
还没有
Well, not yet.
这样  你要不先回去练习备选歌曲吧
Well, why don't we go back and work on that one, okay?
如果在娜娜·诺多曼面前
I mean, look, if you play like that
你还是这样子表演的话
in front of Nana Noodleman...
乔尼
Johnny?
我们这辈子都不愁吃喝啦  兄弟们
We are set for life now, boys!
什么情况  乔尼呢
What's going on? Where's Johnny?
他不在这儿
He's not here.
快跑
Run!
我死定了
I'm dead.
我终将见证  这不是个梦
I can finally see, it's not just a dream
释放自我  突破一切
When you set it all free
等等  我看一下
Okay, wait, let me see.
释放自我  突破一切
When you set it all free, all free, all free
不  老妈  我没交到什么朋友
No, mom, I have not made any friends.
你当这里是哪里  幼儿园吗
What do you think this is, kindergarten?
要不是你冲着警察大声嚷嚷
If you hadn't squealed to the cops,
我也不会在这里了
I wouldn't be in here right now.
亲爱的  你什么时候才出狱
Honey, when are you getting out?
我只会在这里关几年啦
I'm only gonna be in here for a few years.
你把钱藏哪儿了
Well, where'd you hide the money?
你去哪儿了
Where were you?
事实上  我去加油了
Well, thing is, I-I went to get gas, and,
少骗我
Don't lie to me!
我在彩排
I was at a rehearsal.
彩排  彩排什么
Rehearsal? For what?
我参加了歌唱比赛
I was at a singing contest.
爸爸  我真的很抱歉
Look, dad, I'm... I'm sorry.
我只是不想跟着你混帮派
I just don't want to be in your gang.
-我想成为一个歌手  -歌手
- I want to be a singer. - Singer?
不  爸爸  没事的  没事的
Look, dad, no, it's okay, it's okay.
我可以赚回保释金的
I can get the bail money.
比赛有奖金的  有十万呢
There's a prize. It's $100,000...
我怎么会有你这么个儿子
How did I end up with a son like you, eh?
你身上没有一点我的影子
You're nothing like me.
以前没有  之后更不会有
You never were, and you never will be.
我会救你出来的  爸爸  等等
I'll get you out! Dad, wait!
我会拿到奖金的  我发誓
I'll get the money! I promise!
乔尼
天生的歌手
海选成绩出色
乔尼
Johnny!
你...你吓死我了
You... you gave me a fright there.
抱歉  我不是故意的  我只是
Sorry. I didn't mean to. I just...
我知道很晚了
Well, I know it's late,
但我真的需要再恶补一下钢琴课
but I could really use some extra piano lessons.
这就对了
That's it.
真不错
That's good.
你开窍了
You're getting it.
洛克超市
真我难掩光芒
True colors are shining through
我看到了你的真我
I see your true colors
温馨提示  15分钟后
Shoppers are reminded the store
我们将会打烊  谢谢惠顾
will close in 15 minutes. Thank you.
Gipsy Kings - "Bamboleo"
♪Este amor llega asi de esta manera♪
♪No tiene la culpa♪
♪Caballo de danza vana♪
♪Porque es muy despreciado, por eso♪
♪Bembele, bembele, bembele, bem-bembele, bembele♪
5号监控
音量
♪Bamboleo, bambolea♪
♪Porque mi vida, yo la prefiero vivir asi♪
♪Porque mi vida, yo la prefiero♪
♪Vivir asi♪
6号通道的那位女士
The lady in aisle six...
您跳得太棒了
That was awesome.
真棒
All right.
穆恩先生  你确定这样合法吗
Mr. Moon, are you sure this is legal?
我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
但假如你一直问个不停的话
All right, but if you keep asking questions,
我们永远别想做完了
we'll never get this done.
现在  打开吧
Now, hit it!
再高点
A little higher.
再高一点点
Just a little bit.
好了  谢谢你
There it is. Thank you.
贴小广告啦
Posters up.
-你们  -快跑
- You! - Now, run away!
给我回来  你们这些搞破坏的
Come back here, you vandals!
诚招鱿鱼
萝丝塔  你看见我的车钥...
Rosita, have you seen my car...
萝丝塔  这是什
Rosita, what the...?
这什么情况
What's going on?
萝丝塔
Rosita!
孩子们  妈妈在哪儿
Kids, where's mommy?
弹得还行吧  克劳利小姐
How's that, Miss Crawly?
抱歉
Sorry.
穆恩先生叫大家现在去后台集合
Mr. Moon would like everyone to meet backstage
趁她还没来
before she arrives.
释放自我  突破一切
When you set it all free, all free, all free
释放自我
You set it all free
你自己写的
You wrote that?
是啊
Uh... yeah.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
简直棒极了
It's fantastic.
你今天就唱这个了
You've gotta sing that today.
麦克  你打头阵
Mike, you're on first.
没问题
Sure.
稍等我一下
Uh, just a second here.
亲爱的  我正忙呢
Honey, I'm busy.
什么  我听不清
What? I can't hear you.
萝丝塔和甘特  你们接着麦克
Rosita and Gunter, you're on after Mike.
放心吧  老板
You got it, boss.
萝丝塔
Rosita!
酷毙了
Super cool!
你终于满血回归了
You've, like, totally come back.
乔尼  你接着他们登场
Okay, Johnny, you follow them...
什么
What?
啊  行  没问题  我准备好了
Oh, oh, yeah, yeah, I'm ready.
艾什  你
Ash, you're...
在乔尼之后  我明白
After Johnny. I got it.
米娜  你最后的机会了  孩子
And, Meena, last chance, kid.
你今天想加入表演的队伍吗
You want to... you want to join these guys out there today?
我想是想  只是有点害怕
I-I would. I-I just get so scared.
怕是正常的   只是
Sure, you do. All right, but-but...
你知道怎么克服恐惧吧
You know how to get over that, right?
不太知道
Uh, no.
你只管唱歌就好了
You just start singing.
只要你喜欢  那就能做好
Do what you love, then you'll be great
因为你实实在在地在做了
'cause you won't be afraid anymore
你就不会害怕了 对吧
because you'll actually be doing it, right?
你真的喜欢唱歌吗
Look, do you love to sing?
-你是发自内心的喜欢唱歌吗  -当然了
- I mean, do you really love it? - Of course I do.
那昂首挺胸去面对吧  米娜
Then you face this head-on, Meena.
就像我父亲常说的那样
Because, like my dad always said,
"不要让恐惧成为你的绊脚石"
"Don't let fear stop you from doing the thing you love."
行吧  我唱
Uh... Okay, I'll do it.
-太好了  -穆恩先生
- Great. - Mr. Moon!
她来了
She's here.
娜娜奶奶
Nana...!
拥抱我  你想都别想
Oh! Do not even think of embracing me.
听您的
You got it.
艾迪  请你扶娜娜去贵宾包厢吧
Eddie, please show your Nana to the royal box.
我的天  我还没老到走不动道
Oh, for heaven sakes, i'm perfectly capable of walking.
你紧张吗
You nervous?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我都快紧张死了
I'm absolutely terrified.
老大  这是那小子的车吧
Boss. That's his car, isn't it?
那边那辆
Right there.
靠边停
Pull over.
正山小种红茶
Lapsang souchong,
由穆恩先生精心烹煮...
courtesy of Mr. Moo... moo...
棒极了
Wonderful.
亲爱的  演出要开始了
H-honey, honey, the show is starting, all right?
我不方便讲话了  我得挂了
I-I can't talk now. I gotta go.
我当然爱你了
Of course I love you.
不然我为什么给你买钻石耳环...
You think I'd buy you diamond earrings if I didn't...
我的钱呢
Where is my money?
好了  好了  听着  我可能
Okay, okay, listen, listen, I just, uh...
我可能全花光了
I just maybe kind of, uh, spent it all.
你懂吗
You know?
不  不  不  等一下
No, no, no, please, please, wait!
我会还你钱的  我会给你...
I'll give you the money. I'll-I'll get you...
我会还你十万块
I'll get you $100,000!
你这小子从哪儿搞这么大一笔钱
Where are you going to get that kind of money?
穆恩  知道吗
Moon! Okay?
我的钱在穆恩那里
Moon's got my money.
你说的"穆恩"是谁
Who is this "Moon"?
尊贵的大小动物  各位来宾
All creatures great and small,
欢迎来到穆恩剧院
welcome to the Moon Theater.
我是主持人  巴斯特·穆恩
I am your host, Buster Moon, and...
好了
Okay.
请看
Behold!
世上首个全灯光照明舞台
The very first stage lit entirely by...
纯鱿鱼打造
Squid power.
♪Flashing lights♪
干得漂亮  伙计们
Beautiful work, guys.
现在跟着我踩节奏吧
Now just follow me on the beat.
♪Flashing lights♪
正如各位所见  这并不是个普通的剧院
And as you can see, this is no ordinary theater.
这是一座奇幻与魔法的殿堂
This is a palace of wonder and magic.
♪Flashing lights♪
♪As I recall I know you love to show off♪
他做到了
He's done it!
他真的做到了  奶奶
He's really done it, Nana!
♪But I never thought that you would take it this far♪
我的天
Oh, goodness.
下面有请我们的首位参赛者
Now welcome our first contestant.
你们哪个是穆恩
Which one of you is Moon?
你们不能就这么闯进来
you can't just barge in here.
你认识这小子吗
You know this guy?
-麦克  -说对了
-Mike? -Right.
这位麦克说他的钱在你这里
Mike here says you got his money
就在那个箱子里
and it's in that box.
不  不  不  等一下
No, no, no, no, no, just hold on a moment here.
那是奖金 不属于麦克
That's prize money, and it's not Mike's
除非他能公平竞争...
unless he wins it fair and...
-把钱给他  -好吧  好吧
-Give him the money! -Okay, okay.
你带走吧  整个箱子
Take it. The whole chest.
都是你的了  可以了吗
It's yours, okay? All right here.
打开
Open it.
打开  你说我吗
Open it? I-I... no. Me?
快打开
Open it!
好吧  我只是
Okay, no, I-I...
我其实并没有钥匙
I just don't... I don't have the keys,
你要不等会儿再来
so maybe you can come back later?
闪开
Get out of the way!
不  不  不要  住手
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Wait!
这就对了嘛
there you go.
大块头抡球棍就行嘛
Big guy with a bat.
压根儿不需要钥匙嘛
Who needs keys, right? All right, well, let...
现在来把账结清吧
Let's get this thing squared up now.
什么...
What the...?
就这些
That's it?
就这点东西
That's all there is?
他撒谎了
He lied.
穆恩骗了我们所有人
Moon lied to us all.
等一下我可以解释清楚
Well, wait a second. I can explain. Okay?
他才是罪魁祸首  跟我没关系
He's your problem, not me.
这箱子就是个道具
This is just a prop.
所以十万块奖金呢
So, where's the $100,000?
你在开玩笑吗
You're kidding.
你到底在想什么
What's the big idea?
你白白浪费了所有人的...
What a huge waste of everyone's
这只是...
this was just...
巴斯特  小心
Buster, look out!
我卡住了
I'm stuck!
巴斯特  这里快塌了  快跑
Buster, it's falling! Let go!
好了  好了  稳住  亲爱的  稳住
Okay, okay, okay, steady, girl. Steady...
不  不  不
No, no, no, no...!
大家都还好吧
Is everyone okay?
奶奶
Nana!
真的对不起  我只是...
I-I-I'm so sorry. I-I just...
不  不  不  别走
No, no, no, no, no, don't... Don't go!
有人看见我的玻璃眼球了吗
Has anyone seen my glass eye?
在这里  我找到了  克劳利小姐
Oh, it-it... It's right here, Miss Crawly. I've got it.
小心
Look out!
♪Once there was a way to get back homeward♪
不
No.
♪Once there was a way to get back home♪
穆恩洗车行
爸爸
Oh, dad.
我对不起您
I'm so sorry.
♪Boy, you gotta carry that weight♪
麦克哪去了
Where is Mike?
他应该是死了
He must be dead.
♪Carry that weight a long time♪
行了  撤吧
Come on, let's go.
♪Boy, you gotta carry that weight♪
妈妈你在哪儿
Mommy, where are you?
♪Carry that weight a long time♪
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
妈妈来了
Mommy's here!
我正站在事发现场  朱迪
I'm standing at the scene right now, Judy,
我只能说这真是一个奇迹
and I can tell you it is a miracle
如此严重的灾难居然零伤亡
anyone survived this unbelievable disaster.
穆恩剧院倒塌
♪Golden slumbers fill your eyes♪
♪Sleep pretty darling and do not cry♪
SFJ银行财产
♪And I will sing a lullaby♪
在今天  巴斯特·穆恩
Um, yeah, Buster Moon certainly
彻底摧毁了整栋剧院
brought down the house once and for all today.
疯狂考拉摧毁大剧院
然而穆恩先生并未对此作出回应
And, although Mr. Moon has not been available for questions,
有未证实消息称
Unconfirmed reports suggest
他私自建造室内蓄水箱
he was responsible for building a water tank
但水箱崩塌从而冲垮了整幢建筑
that exploded and flooded the building.
据称
I've been told
参与穆恩表演秀的250只鱿鱼
The 250 squid who had been part of Moon's display
事实上曾受雇于...
are, in fact, employees...
-艾迪  -一家三星级餐厅花枝居...
- Eddie? -...Of three-star restaurant Le calmar...
有人在敲门
There's someone at the door.
事故中并未有鱿鱼受到伤害
...and that none of them were harmed during the incident.
而它们是否会重操旧业尚未...
Whether they will be returning to their usual work is not yet...
不是吧
Oh, no.
穆恩先生
Mr. Moon?
行了  穆恩
Come on, Moon,
你不能一直躲在朋友的泳池小屋里
You can't just hide out in your buddy's pool house.
对呀  我们只是想来看看您还好吗
Yeah, we just want to make sure you're all right, that's all.
-穆恩先生  -您还好吧
- Hey, Mr. Moon. - You okay?
几位  对发生的事情我很抱歉
Guys, look, I-I-I'm sorry about what happened,
然后奖金也...
and-and the prize money and...
没关系的
Oh, it's okay.
不  这些都有关系
No, none of this is okay.
至少我们都没受伤
At least we're all in one piece.
对呀  您知道吗
Yeah, and you know what,
我们一定能找到其他地方演出
I bet we can find some other place to put the show on.
-对吧  -是啊
- Right? - Yeah.
演出
The show?
大伙  我完了
Guys, I'm done.
-你认真的吗  -什么叫完了  得了吧
-Are you serious? -What do you mean, done? Come on!
你们没看这个吗
Didn't you see this?
这里说我是危害社会的危险分子
Look, it says I'm a danger to society.
什么
What?
"一个满口谎言的失败者
"A deluded, washed-up charlatan
一生平平  了无成就"
who never had a hit in his career."
得了吧  你不会相信这些的
Oh, come on, you don't believe all that.
不  我信
Yeah, I do.
听着  不止是你失去了一些东西
Listen, you're not the only one who lost something here.
-我们都是  -对呀
- We all did. - Yeah!
我连跟父亲讲话的机会都没了
I mean, I lost any chance of ever speaking
就为了能够演出
to my dad again over this show.
-抱歉  -穆恩先生  不要...
- Sorry. - Oh, Mr. Moon, don't...
算了吧
Ah, forget about it.
这算什么  搞不懂了
What is this? I don't understand.
算了  我们走吧
Come on, let's get out of here.
穆恩先生
Mr. Moon?
米娜  请回吧
Meena, please.
我为您烤了个蛋糕
Um, I-I baked a cake for you
因为我知道您现在一定很难过
'cause, well, I know you're sad right now
也许提不起勇气来...
and probably afraid to try again and...
是啊  我怕了
Yeah, I am afraid.
我怕这个
I'm afraid that this...
这个  现在的我  这就是我
This, me, right now, this is who I am.
这就是我的命
This is... This is my lot for life--
我达不到我父亲的期望
that I'm not the guy that my dad wanted me to be,
差了十万八千里
Not by a million miles.
可是您告诉我...
But, but you told me...
什么  我说了什么
What? What? What did I say?
呃  就是
Well, you know,
"不要让恐惧成为你的绊脚石"
"Don't let fear stop you from doing the thing you love."
得了吧  那就是一些愚蠢的老掉牙的话
Ah, come... th-that's just a bunch of stupid, corny...
不是这样的
No, it's not.
你不会真以为你能成为歌手吧
What, you really believe that you're gonna be a singer?
当然有可能啊
Well, yeah, maybe.
那你就和我一样蠢到家了
Well, then you're just as big a fool as I am!
听着  孩子
Look, kid.
你和我  我们害怕都是有理由的
You and me, we-we're both afraid for good reason.
因为打心底里我们就知道
Right, 'cause deep down we know...
我们就是没这个本事
...we just don't have what it takes.
♪Wake me up before you go-go♪
我醒了  我醒了
I'm awake!  I'm awake!
-怎么了  巴斯特  -艾迪
-Hey, Buster. -Hey, Eddie.
老兄你去哪儿了  你还好吧
Man, where'd you go? Are you okay?
听着  你可以来找我吗
Listen, could you meet me at the corner
就在丁斯代尔路和雷明顿大街的路口
of Dinsdale and Lemington?
现在吗
Now?
对  拜托了
Yeah, please.
还有你能不能
And could you, uh...
你能给我带条泳裤吗
Could you bring me a spare speedo?
泳裤
Speedo?
丁斯代尔路  雷明顿街
穆恩洗车点
您好  克劳利小姐
Hey, Miss Crawly.
你好呀  艾迪
Oh, hello, Eddie.
泳裤带来了吗
Did you bring the speedo?
-带了  给你  -太好了
-The... oh, yeah, uh, here. -Great.
你真是我兄弟  艾迪
You're a real pal, Eddie.
我们的第一位顾客
Oh, our first customer.
克劳利小姐  把水桶装满吧
Miss Crawly, fill the bucket.
稍等片刻  先生
Be right with you, sir.
等等  你在做什么
Wait. What are you doing?
我现在唯一的谋生技能
The only other job I know.
真庆幸父亲没看到我这样
Just glad my dad isn't here to see this.
克劳利小姐  你可以...
Miss Crawly, if you would...
《图兰朵-今夜无人入睡》  普契尼
多谢了
Thanks.
好了  该干活儿了
Well, gotta go to work. Uh...
待会儿见  艾迪
I'll see you around, Eddie.
♪Ma il mio mistero e' chiuso in me,♪
♪Il nome mio nessun sapra♪
♪No, no, sulla tua bocca lo diro♪
快点  我没工夫陪你耗一天
Come on! I ain't got all day!
♪Quando la luce splendera♪
好的  没问题
Yeah, yeah...
算了吧
Ah, forget it.
慢死了  老兄
Too slow, dude.
稍等片刻  先生
One moment, please, sir.
你知道跌入谷底的好处是什么吗
Well, you know the good thing about hitting rock bottom?
因为只有一个选择了  那就是向上
There's only one way left to go, and that's up.
♪Vincero Vincero♪
来吧  你清洗  我擦干
Come on. You wash, I'll dry.
谢谢你  克劳利小姐
Thank you, Miss Crawly.
巴斯特  你要去哪儿
Buster, where are you going?
♪I couldn't feel, so I tried to touch♪
♪I've told the truth, I didn't come to fool you♪
♪And even though it all went wrong♪
♪I'll stand before the Lord of Song♪
♪With nothing on my tongue but Hallelujah♪
♪Hallelujah♪
♪Hallelujah...♪
我...
I, uh...
你觉得如果面对着真实的观众
Do you think you could sing like that
你还能唱得这么棒吗
in front of a real audience?
我不知道  但我想试试
I don't know, but I want to try.
好
Good.
因为我想见识一下
'Cause I want to see it.
是吗  真的吗
We are? Seriously?
天啊  好的
Oh, my gosh! Okay.
好的好的  我马上过去
Okay, yes, I'll be right over.
喂
Hello?
你好啊  穆恩先生
Oh, hello, Mr. Moon.
有人说他是本市史上最差的演出经理
Some say he's the worst showman this city's ever seen.
有人说他就是一瘟神
Some say he's a walking disaster.
穆恩剧院直播
一个疯子
A loose Cannon.
明晚  巴斯特·穆恩这个名字
Well, tomorrow night, the name Buster Moon
将永远被记录在娱乐历史中
will go down in entertainment history once and for all,
因为他和他纠集的一帮装模作样的外行
as he and this bunch of bumbling amateurs
直播表演
想要重演那场摧毁了他的剧院的表演
attempt to restage the show that brought down his theater.
♪Pressure♪
♪Pushing down on me♪
♪Pressing down on you♪
♪No man ask for♪
♪Under pressure♪
♪That burns a building down♪
♪Splits a family in two♪
♪Puts people on streets♪
♪That's OK♪
♪It's the terror of knowing♪
舞台
♪What this world is about♪
♪Watching some good friends♪
♪Screaming let me out!♪
♪Pray tomorrow gets me higher♪
♪Pressure on people♪
♪People on streets♪
别担心  麦克  我全都原谅你
Ah, don't you worry, Mike. All is forgiven.
你毫发无损地回来了就好
Just glad you're back in one piece.
你真是太好了  穆恩先生
Oh, yeah, you're too kind, Mr. Moon.
那...奖金呢
And, uh, the... the prize money?
奖金...这次...是真的了吧
It's, uh... I mean, it's... it's real this time, right?
没有奖金  因为这不是比赛
There is no prize money, 'cause there's no competition.
今晚你们是为自己而唱
Tonight you're singing for yourselves.
两分钟  各位  最后检查
Two minutes, everybody. Final checks.
为自己而唱
Singing for ourselves?
难以置信  这是  他是
Unbelievable. What-what-what is...? Who's he...?
真是疯了  我要走了
This is crazy. I'm out of here.
你好啊
Hello!
我们...我们要在这儿演出
Uh, we-we're... We're putting on a show here.
-走吧  -你们都来看看吧
- Come on. - You all should come and see it.
你  来吧  来吧  伙计
You! Come on! Come on, fella!
真的会很精彩的
It's going to be really good.
我们这位新来的舞台管理怎么样
How's our new stagehand getting on?
-他学得很快  -一切准备就绪
- He's learning fast. - All set and standing by!
我喜欢这耳机
I love this headset!
观众已就坐  穆恩先生
The audience are in their seats, Mr. Moon.
太好了
Great!
-卡斯帕  -就这些
- Caspar! - That's all?
裤子穿好  年轻人
Get your pants back on, young man!
求你们了  别闹了
Please, you guys, please.
快坐下
Please sit down!
把鞋穿上  快穿
Hey, put your shoes back on right now!
佐伊  我看见了  住手
Zoe, I saw that! Stop it!
里奥  太恶心了
And, Leo, that is disgusting!
约翰  我在这家电视台
Well, John, I've covered many disasters
报道过很多灾难  但这一次肯定是
for this network, but this is sure to...
他们要开演了
They're about to start.
好了  伙计们  听好
Okay, guys, listen up.
我要告诉你们
Look, I gotta tell you, um,
今晚外面没有多少观众
there's not much of an audience out there tonight.
但你们知道吗
But you know what?
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
真的不重要
It really doesn't.
因为今晚属于我们
'Cause tonight is our night.
无论发生什么
And whatever happens,
我只想让你们知道
I just want you all to know
能和你们一起完成这件事我有多自豪
how proud I am to be a part of this with you.
祝你好运  穆恩先生
Good luck, Mr. Moon.
好运  各位
Good luck, every...
抱歉
Sorry.
有点切早了  别担心
Just jumped the cue there. Don't worry.
我会熟练掌握用法的
I... I-I'm gonna get the hang of this.
开始吧
Here we go.
各位来宾  尊贵的大小动物们
All creatures great and small,
欢迎来到
welcome to...
你们好啊
Oh, hello there.
太好了
Great.
欢迎来到我们焕然一新的露天剧院
Welcome to our newly refurbished, open-air theater.
-我是主持人  -准备好了吗  大块头
- Yes, I am your host... - You ready, big guy?
好了
Ja!
我完全准备好了
I'm, like, totally ready.
好了
All right.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
有请甘特和萝丝塔
Gunter and Rosita!
Taylor Swift - "Shake It Off"
♪I stay up too late♪
♪Got nothing in my brain♪
♪That's what people say, mmm-mmm♪
♪I go on too many dates♪
♪But I can't make them stay♪
♪At least that's what people say, mmm-mmm♪
♪That's what people say, mmm-mmm♪
你看到了吗
Are you getting this?
♪But I keep cruising♪
♪Can't stop, won't stop moving♪
♪It's like I got this music♪
♪In my mind, saying, "It's gonna be alright."♪
♪I never miss a beat♪
♪I'm lightning on my feet♪
♪And that's what they don't see, mmm-mmm♪
♪That's what they don't see, mmm-mmm♪
♪'Cause the players gonna play, play, play, play, play♪
♪And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate♪
♪Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake♪
♪I shake it off, I shake it off♪
♪And the fakers gonna fake, fake, fake, fake, fake♪
♪And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate♪
他们真是太厉害了
Aren't they great?
♪Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake♪
你逗我呢吧
What, are you kidding me?
像是果冻跳舞一样
It's like watching jell-o dancing around.
说得好像你多厉害似的  小东西
Like you could do any better, pip-squeak.
行了  行了
All right, all right, all right.
你想看伟大的表演吗
You want to see something great?
那我就让你瞧瞧
I'll show you great.
♪Heart-breakers gonna break♪
♪Fakers gonna fake♪
♪I'm just gonna shake♪
♪I shake it off, I shake it off♪
♪Shake it off, I shake it off♪
♪I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off♪
甘特和萝丝塔
Gunter and Rosita!
孩子们  不  回座位上去
Kids, no. Back to your seats.
-表演还...  -好了  好了
- The show's still... - Okay, okay.
诺曼
Norman!
太棒了  猪猪能量
All right! Piggy power!
唱得太棒了
That was great!
看来喜欢刚才表演的不止我一个人
Well, it seems I'm not the only one who actually enjoyed that.
渐渐开始有观众开始入场了
Crowds are beginning to arrive at the scene.
帮帮我
Help!
真抱歉  穆恩先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. Moon.
乔尼  你下一个上
Johnny, you're on next.
Elton John - "I'm Still Standing"
♪You could never know what it's like♪
♪Your blood like winter freezes just like ice♪
♪And there's a cold lonely light that shines from you♪
♪You'll wind up like the wreck you hide♪
♪Behind that mask you use♪
♪And did you think this fool could never win♪
♪Well look at me, I'm coming back again♪
什么玩意  小点声听见没
What is that? Turn it down, will you?
♪I got a taste of love in a simple way♪
♪And if you need to know while I'm still standing♪
你们没听见吗
Didn't you hear me?
我说小点声...
I said turn it...
♪You just fade away♪
乔尼
Johnny?
♪Don't you know I'm still standing better than I ever did♪
♪Looking like a true survivor♪
乔尼
Johnny!
♪Feeling like a little kid♪
是乔尼
It's Johnny!
♪I'm still standing after all this time♪
我儿子
That's my son!
♪Picking up the pieces of my life♪
我儿子
My son...
♪Without you on my mind♪
♪I'm still standing♪
搞什么
What the...?
♪Once I never could hope to win♪
♪You starting down the road leaving me again♪
♪The threats you made were meant to cut me down♪
♪And if our love was just a circus♪
♪You'd be a clown by now♪
♪Don't you know I'm still standing better than I ever did♪
♪Looking like a true survivor♪
♪Feeling like a little kid♪
♪I'm still standing after all this time♪
♪Picking up the pieces of my life♪
♪Without you on my mind♪
♪I'm still standing♪
精彩不精彩
What about that, huh?
大家给乔尼掌声鼓励
Give it up for Johnny, folks.
太棒了
Yeah!
乔尼  乔尼
Johnny! Johnny!
怎么这幅表情  你唱得超棒啊
What's with the face? You were great.
大家都喜欢你
They loved you.
是啊  谢谢  萝丝塔
Yeah, thanks, Rosita.
好了
All right.
欢迎各位刚刚入场的观众
Welcome to all you newcomers.
你们正好可以认识下一位歌手
You are just in time to meet a teenager
我们这位少女刚刚被男友甩了
who was recently dumped by her boyfriend.
很难过  对吧
I know, right?
但她要用自己的歌
But she's gonna chase those blues away
一扫阴霾
with a song of her very own.
请允许我介绍这位歌坛新秀  艾什
Allow me to introduce the singing sensation, Ash.
朱迪斯
Judith?
你们这都是非法入侵私人财产
You are all trespassing on private property.
-什么  -必须马上离开
- What?! - And you will leave right now.
我没...  不不不  朱迪斯
I didn't... no, no, no, no, no, no, Judith...
所有人
All of you.
你想干什么
What're you doing!
Scarlett Johansson - "Set It All Free"
♪I followed my heart into the fire♪
♪Got burned, got broken down by desire♪
♪I tried, I tried but the smoke in my eyes♪
♪Left me blurry♪
♪Blurry and blind♪
♪I picked all the pieces up off the ground♪
♪I've burned all my fingers but that's gone now♪
♪Got the glue in my hands and sticking to the plan♪
我要报警了
I am calling the police!
♪Sticking to the plan that says "I can"♪
♪Do anything at all♪
♪I can do anything at all♪
♪This is my kiss-goodbye♪
♪You can stand alone and watch me fly♪
♪Cause nothing's keeping me down♪
♪Gonna light it all up♪
♪Come on and say right now, right now, right now♪
不是吧
Seriously?
她哪有那么厉害
She's not even that good.
就是  就是
Yeah, yeah, totally.
♪This is my big hello♪
♪Cause I'm hearing, never letting go♪
♪I can finally see, it's not just a dream♪
♪When you set it all free, all free, all free♪
♪You set it all free♪
♪This is my big hello♪
♪Cause I'm hearing, never letting go♪
♪I can finally see, it's not just a dream♪
♪When you set it all free, all free, all free♪
♪You set it all free♪
你们没事吧
You guys okay?
艾什  艾什  艾什
Ash! Ash! Ash! Ash!
Ash! Ash! Ash!
多好听啊
What about that?
我们目睹了一颗真正的摇滚巨星冉冉升起
We just witnessed the birth of a genuine rock star!
穆恩  你...这儿扎了根刺
Moon, you... You've got some stuck here.
虽然他身材迷你
He may be tiny,
但他极高的天分无法否认
but there is no denying his enormous talent.
欢迎麦克登上舞台
Would you please welcome to the stage Mike.
你还好意思回来
What are you doing back here?
别紧张  亲爱的
Relax, sweetheart.
我就是来让你们这帮笨蛋瞧瞧
Just came back to show you bozos
行家怎么唱的
how it's really done.
看着点
Now, watch this.
Frank Sinatra - "My Way"
♪And now♪
♪The end is near♪
♪And so I face♪
♪The final curtain♪
♪My friend♪
♪I'll say it clear♪
♪I'll state my case♪
♪Of which I'm certain♪
♪I've lived♪
老大  是他
Boss, that is him!
♪A life that's full♪
是麦克
That is Mike!
♪I've travelled each♪
♪And every highway♪
♪And more, much more than this♪
♪I did it my way♪
♪Regrets♪
♪I've had a few♪
♪But then again♪
♪Too few to mention♪
♪I did what I had to do♪
♪And saw it through without exemption♪
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
♪I planned each charted course♪
♪Each careful step♪
♪Along the byway♪
♪And more, much more than this♪
♪I did it my way♪
你一定是在逗我
You gotta be kidding me.
♪For what is a mouse♪
♪What has he got♪
♪If not himself♪
♪Then he has not♪
♪To say the things♪
♪He truly feels♪
♪And not the words of one who kneels♪
♪The record shows♪
♪I took the blows♪
没有发现  我跟丢了嫌疑人
Negative. I've lost sight of the suspect
终止追捕
and am terminating pursuit.
♪And did it♪
♪My way♪
那小东西原来真的很厉害
That pip-squeak really was great.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
行了  你们太好了  真的
Oh, please. You're too kind, really.
看我  我都骄傲了
Look at me. I'm turning red.
得了  我受不了了
Stop. I can't take it.
继续鼓掌  别停
Keep... keep it coming.
我得回去了
Well, I better get back.
他们会想我怎么样了
They'll be wondering what happened to me.
你会去探监的  对吧
You'll visit me, though, yeah?
当然会了
Yeah, course I will.
再见  儿子
See you, son.
今晚还有最后一个节目
We have one final act for you tonight.
请欢迎有生以来第一次
Would you please welcome to the stage
登上舞台表演的
for her first ever live appearance...
米娜
Meena.
Meena?
她还没出来
Is she coming out?
米娜  怎么了  你没事吧
Meena, what's wrong? Are you okay?
我动不了了
I can't move.
我吓坏了
I'm... I'm terrified.
把手给我  孩子
Give me your hand, kid.
深呼吸
Okay, deep breaths.
Deep breaths.
想想我对你说的
And remember what I told you.
你只要开口唱
You will not feel afraid anymore
就不会再害怕了
if you just start singing.
-米娜  -米娜
- Meena! - Meena!
我可以的...
I can do it... okay.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
好
Okay.
唱吧
Sing.
好
Okay.
Stevie Wonder - "Don't You Worry 'Bout a Thing"
♪Everybody's got a thing♪
♪But some don't know how to handle it♪
♪Always reachin' out in vain♪
♪Accepting the things not worth having but♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing, mama♪
♪Cause I'll be standing on the side♪
♪When you check it out♪
♪They say your style of life's a drag♪
♪And that you must go other places♪
♪Just don't you feel too bad♪
♪When you get fooled by smiling faces♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing, baby♪
♪Cause I'll be standing on the side, when you check it♪
♪Out♪
♪When you get it off...your trip♪
哥们  等等  我们能谈妥的  对吧
Guys, guys, wait. We can talk this over, right?
我们都是讲理的人
We're all reasonable individuals here.
快上车
Get in! Quick!
谢谢  宝贝
Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
差一点啊
That was close.
是啊
Yeah.
♪Everybody needs a change♪
♪A chance to check out the new♪
♪You're the only one who sees♪
♪The changes you take yourself through♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing♪
一起来
Come on!
♪Don't you worry♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing, mama♪
♪Cause I'll be standing, I'll be standing♪
♪For you♪
♪Don't you worry 'bout a thing♪
米娜  你做到了
Meena! You did it!
她做到了
She did it!
上  上
Go, go!
爸爸  我真希望你能看到
Oh, dad, I wish you could see this.
银行财产
售出
娜娜·诺多曼
♪Once, there was a way♪
♪To get back homeward♪
♪To get back home♪
♪Sleep, pretty darling, do not cry♪
♪And I will sing a lullaby♪
盛大重开
大家准备好了吗
Everybody ready?
各位来宾  大小动物们
All creatures great and small,
欢迎来到全新的穆恩剧院
welcome to the new Moon Theater.